Xiaotian Wang

Career Objective - Software Engineer & Developer

(937) 607-0249 | xiaotian.wang_2020@outlook.com linkedIn.com/in/xt-wang | wang-xiaotian.github.io



PERSONAL PERSPECTIVE

I am a U.S. Citizen. I enjoy exploring innovative ideas and tackling challenges outside of my comfort zone, from an artificial intelligence laboratory to the U.S. Army Ranger School. My diverse experience and growth mindset can be an asset to the employer.

EDUCATION

M.S. in Computer Engineering, Wright State University, OH	Aug 2015
M.S. in Industrial and Human Factor Engineering, Wright State University, OH	Jun 2013
B.S. in Supply Chain, Dalian Jiaotong University, China	Jul 2009

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Technology Associate (MTA 98-361) Software Development Fundamentals

CORE SKILLS

• C# • ASP.Net Core • Azure • Cloud • T-SQL • JavaScript • CSS • HTML • Python • Java • Prolog

CAREER HISTORY

Cloud Application Developer

Sep 2020 - Present

Microsoft Software \$ Systems Academy, WA

- Designed a web game to boost preschoolers' math learning experience.
- Eliminated the math learning anxiety by an animated character and interactive game environment.
- Encouraged students to practice fundamental math concepts while collecting treasures.

Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) System Supervisor

Jan 2016 - Present

U.S. Army, Joint Base Lewis-McChord, WA

- Designed an application that eliminated a million dollars inventory loss and improved inventory accuracy by 40%.
- Analyzed data to generate business intelligence reports that led to sustaining 95%+ equipment readiness.
- Maintained records for 1000+ equipment and managed a warehouse of logistics planning systems.
- Developed training plans and individual professional roadmaps for 8 soldiers.

Research Assistant in Artificial Intelligence

Jan 2013 – Dec 2015

Wright State University, Dayton, OH

- Publication Mission-Aware Vulnerability Assessment for Cyber-Physical Systems, 2015 IEEE Trustcom/BigDataSE Conference.
- Integrated formal methods, including symbolic execution, logic programming, and linear optimization, for vulnerability assessment.
- Designed a platform by using Java, Prolog and MySQL to demonstrate and test the performance of the vulnerability assessment of a cyber-physical system.

HONORS AND AWARDS

- US Army Ranger Tab, Jul 2019
- Non-commissioned Officer Evaluation Report Top 1%, Nov 2019